<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on d3adb5's personal website</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on d3adb5's personal website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 18:30:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d3adb5.net/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building myself a desktop PC</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/building-a-computer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/building-a-computer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year I decided to build myself a computer, and use it to start playing
some graphically demanding PC games. The plan had existed for a while, but was
accelerated after I broke my Arch Linux installation on my Dell Optiplex 3080
Micro &amp;mdash; I blogged about it previously &amp;mdash; and decided I needed to ensure I
had backup installations and SSDs to fall back onto in times of need. In this
article I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Experiencing 64 GB of RAM + 80 GB of swap</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/lots-of-ram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/lots-of-ram/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the past couple of days I have been using a machine with &lt;em&gt;64 GB of RAM,&lt;/em&gt;
and &lt;em&gt;80 GB of swap space.&lt;/em&gt; This amount of computer memory is more than I have
ever conceived using. No, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not gaming on it,&lt;/strong&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m not a Java
developer running IntelliJ IDEA with 20+ projects open at the same time.
However, language servers and other applications I use on a daily basis have
made me rethink how much memory I really need.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How does a micro form factor PC perform?</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/using-a-micro-pc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/using-a-micro-pc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I started looking into building myself a reasonable desktop
so I could finally graduate from my ThinkPad X220. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, the X220
is pretty neat and will still work for a long time, but sometimes its fan would
go turbo mode while running relatively simple programs like Telegram Desktop
and Discord. You could chalk that up to the applications not being well
optimized &lt;em&gt;&amp;mdash; and that is specially true for the latter example &amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt; but at
some point you give in and start looking to replace the hardware that was
already meant for just office work &lt;strong&gt;when it came out back in 2011.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>