<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rants on d3adb5's personal website</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/tags/rants/</link><description>Recent content in Rants on d3adb5's personal website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 18:30:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://d3adb5.net/tags/rants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building myself a desktop PC</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/building-a-computer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/building-a-computer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year I decided to build myself a computer, and use it to start playing
some graphically demanding PC games. The plan had existed for a while, but was
accelerated after I broke my Arch Linux installation on my Dell Optiplex 3080
Micro &amp;mdash; I blogged about it previously &amp;mdash; and decided I needed to ensure I
had backup installations and SSDs to fall back onto in times of need. In this
article I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How a keyboard layout ruined my daily life</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/unusual-keyboard-shenanigans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/unusual-keyboard-shenanigans/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using computers for quite some time. Though BBSes, Usenet, IRC, and
many forums came way before I was even born &amp;mdash; I&amp;rsquo;m relatively young, come on
&amp;mdash; I was a netizen before the shift towards video conferencing and voice
calls. Consequently I grew up primarily using the keyboard to communicate with
people online. &lt;em&gt;Growing up in Brazil,&lt;/em&gt; I was raised using the &lt;em&gt;modern ABNT2
keyboard layout&lt;/em&gt; to type Portuguese, and that has sadly stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Writing your program in C can make it slower</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/c-isnt-string-friendly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/c-isnt-string-friendly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me what I thought of programming about a decade ago, my &lt;em&gt;young,
inexperienced, zealot self&lt;/em&gt; would have likely told you everybody should be
programming in C, so that all programs could be really fast, and that
programmers who complained about the language were just too lazy to deal with
memory allocation and pointers. &lt;strong&gt;How mistaken I was!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I attributed every bit of slow software or transition to &lt;em&gt;lazy
Java programmers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sonos speakers are actually pretty good</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/sonos-speakers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/sonos-speakers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last Christmas I got my wife a couple of Sonos One speakers so she wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
have to listen to music through her phone&amp;rsquo;s tiny speaker. She does have a good
pair of headphones, and the audio quality of AirPods is decent enough I&amp;rsquo;m in no
hurry to replace any of those. However, when we listen to music together over a
game of &lt;em&gt;Scrabble&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Bananagrams,&lt;/em&gt; iPhone or iPad speakers simply won&amp;rsquo;t cut
it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Back to playing games because of Breath of the Wild</title><link>https://d3adb5.net/blog/back-to-playing-botw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://d3adb5.net/blog/back-to-playing-botw/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My wife has recently started playing &lt;em&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;
on her Nintendo Switch OLED. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching her play, and it rekindled my
interest in the game in a way that I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing video
games on and off since I was a kid, but honestly believed that I was done with
them. However, watching her play the game and seeing how much she enjoys it, I
couldn&amp;rsquo;t help grabbing my Switch and continuing from where I left off.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>